Guide to The Alfred C. Berol Collection of Lewis Carroll 1845 - 1993 MSS 057
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 6: Provenance
  - Subseries 6E Printed Materials. (See Ovrsize Box 14).
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April & Dec. 1941. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Jan. & Feb. 1942. (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Jan. & March 1945. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April 1945. (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April & May 1945. (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April 1946. (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & Oct. 1946. (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Dec. 1947. (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & April 1949. (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. 1950. (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March & Oct. 1951. (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. & Dec. 1951. (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Feb. 1952, Feb. 1953, & Dec. 1954., 1952-1954 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Feb., April & May 1955. (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March 1960 & Nov. 1961., 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March & Dec. 1962. (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & Dec. 1963. (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. 1964 & May 1968., 1964, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Ritter-Hopson Galleries, Dec. 1932. (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Scribner"s, Cat. 137., undated (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Chas. J. Sawyer, Ltd., 1959. (Box 19, Folder 45)
- Oversize - Series 2
  - Subseries 2B: Corrected Proofs
    - Dodgson, Charles Euclid Proofs with Ms Corrections, 4pp [n.p.] [n.d.] (X 150, X 150a, X 151, X 151a) 17 x 11., undated; 1903 (Box 12, Folder 511A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.] Not numbered by Frost but "86134" in upper right of each page. 17 x 5.5., undated; 1904 (Box 12, Folder 511B)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 6pp [n.p.] [n.d.]. 17.5 x 6., undated; 1906 (Box 12, Folder 511C)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 6pp [n.p.] [n.d.] Set is held together with a tack., undated (Box 12, Folder 511C)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for The Game of Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.]., undated (Box 12, Folder 511C)
  - Subseries 2C: Manuscripts by others.
    - Dodgson, Margaret "Miss Jones" Song Ms, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.] (XX 567)., undated (Box 12, Folder 511)
- Oversize - Series 3
  - Subseries 3B: Drawings by others
    - Furniss, Harry Untitled Drawings, 1p [n.p.], [n.d.] Proofs for Sylvie and Bruno with Dodgson holograph Commentary., undated (Box 12, Folder 542A)
- Oversize - Series 4
  - Subseries 4A.
    - Photo of [Terry, Ellen] Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number [n.n] Figure in a carriage. Labelled "At Moray Lodge". Photo of Florence on verso. Mounted on pasteboard. on loan., undated; 2035 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry, Ellen and Kate Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number none Ellen holds rope Kate bound as Andromeda. Photo of Florence on verso. Mounted on pasteboard on loan., undated; 2036 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry, Florence Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number [n.n] Girl pares fruit with one foot up on box. 8x10. Photos of Kate and Ellen on verso. Mounted on pasteboard on loan., undated; 2037 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry Family Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number[n.n] At the family"s home in Kentish Town on July 15th, 1865. Mounted on Pasteboard 9.5 x 12., 2038 (Box 12, Folder 595B)
- Oversize - Series 5
  - Subseries 5A.
    - Poster for Guinness, Callard and Bowser (12pp)., undated (Box 12, Folder 609)
  - Subseries 5C: Ephemera.
    - The Hollyn Cut-Outs., undated (Box 12, Folder 636A)
    - Moser, Barry Print., undated (Box 12, Folder 636B)
    - Unknown Panorama., undated (Box 12, Folder 640A)
    - (1) Alice and the White Rabbit Macmillan Advertisng Poster, undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (2)The Dodo Presenting the Thimble to Alice Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (3) The Chesire Cat Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (4) The Mad Tea Party Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (5) The Mock Turtle"s Story Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (6)The Trial of the Knave of Hearts Macmillan Advertisng Poster, undated (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - Unknown Wonderland Biscuit Tin (shelved in its own box [10a])., undated (Box 10a, Folder 637C)
  - Subseries 5D: Magazines with Articles on Dodgson and/or his works.
    - The Bakers Dozen., undated (Box 14, Folder 645A)
    - Colliers Magazine April 9, 1949. (Box 14, Folder 645B)
    - The Jabberwock 1888-1898 1932. (Box 14, Folder 645C)
    - The Knight Letter 1974-1985. (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - Life Magazine June 18, 1951 December 25, 1950 June 29, 1959., 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 645E)
    - News From Home: The Firemasters of Charleston 1945. (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - The Queen November 18, 1931. (Box 14, Folder 645G)
    - Realities 1967. (Box 14, Folder 645H)
    - Ringling Brother"s Magazine 1945. (Box 14, Folder 645I)
    - Scientific American April, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 645J)
    - What"s New #197, 1956., undated (Box 14, Folder 645K)
  - Subseries 5G: Theater Materials.
    - Theater Posters for dramatizations of Alice., undated (Box 14, Folder 653A)
    - Poster made for opening of collection at Bobst., undated (Box 14, Folder 653B)
- Oversize - Series 6
  - Subseries 6D: Provenance Notes
    - Provenance information on Dodgson manuscript "A Charade"., undated (Box 14, Folder 725A)
  - Subseries 6E: Printed Materials. (Pamphlets by Lewis Carroll).
    - Brief Method of Dividing a Given Number by 9 or 11. 1897 (copy 1), undated (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - Brief Method of Dividing a Given Number by 9 or 11 1897(copy 2), undated (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - Circular Billiards, for Two Players. 1963., undated (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - "Doublets" from "Vanity Fair," April 19, 1879 (copy 1). (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - "Doublets" from "Vanity Fair," April 19, 1879 (copy 2). (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - Jabberwocky., undated (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - Lists of Institutions., undated (Box 14, Folder 16E)
    - The New Method of Evaluation as Applied to p. 1865., undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Natural Science at Oxford, May 19, 1877. (w/ envelope) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Parliamentary Election, July 4, 1884. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Registration of Parcels, January 1890., undated (Box 14, Folder 17)